Sarath Prakash

<u>sarathprakashofficial@gmail.com</u> | +91 9947311713
Pulikkottil house, Brahmakulam PO, Thrissur, Kerala
More details visit: http://sarathprakash.com/

Summary

I have overall 9+ years of software development experience in IT industry. Successfully implemented more than 15 software projects, participating in full project life cycle. Scaling new heights of success and leaving a mark of excellence in assignments. A challenging career in Business Analysis and to be associated with a progressive organization which can provide me with a dynamic work sphere to extract my inherent skills as a Professional, use and develop my aptitude to further the organization's objectives and attain my career targets in the progress.

Professional Highlights

AGILE METHADOLOGY	80%	AUTOMATE TESTING	80%
MANUAL TESTING	90%	DATABASE TESTING	759
API TESTING	75%	ASP.NET	709
SQL DATABASE	80%	C#	709
MVC 5	90%	DOTNET CORE	809
JAVASCRIPT/JQUERY	60%	HTML/CSS	609

QA Roles & Responsibilities

- 1. Identifying issues and risks in a timely manner on each environment
- 2. Updating the regression pack for providing the best application coverage; supervising the Regression Team & ensuring timely delivery for each regression cycle
- 3. Monitoring testing activities for ensuring the quality and functionality of assigned systems; ensuring timely & accurate test communication with Development Leads, Project Manager & Senior Management throughout the project life-cycle
- 4. Tested penetration testing issues using Burp suite, Cross scripting attacks and fortify fixes
- 5. Following the project life cycle methodology defined under the process framework; ensuring that customer deadlines are met.
- 6. Experience in Agile process and methodologies.
- 7. Involved in Test case review meetings, Scrum discussions, and Retrospective meetings.
- 8. Experience in understanding business and testing requirements.
- 9. Hands-on experience in Database testing

Development Roles & Responsibilities

- 1. Requirements have been documented and get approval from the stack holders.
- 2. Creation of user stories for a sprint and thereby follow scrum methodology for development.
- 3. Done impact analysis on user stories and estimated time effort for the same
- 4. Took the responsibility on project by taking ownership and work all the PBI's bugs, developments and deployment individually
- 5. Participated in solution development, contributed to client discussions and meetings on daily basis.
- 6. Met deliverables as per client expectation.
- 7. Identifying issues and risks in a timely manner; developing/implementing appropriate mitigation & contingency plans
- 8. Worked on fixing penetration testing issues, Cross scripting attacks and fortify fixes
- 9. Worked on technologies such as C#, dotnet core, MVC, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, SQL Server JavaScript and jQuery.
- 10. Creating Database object such as tables and stored procedures.
- 11. Deployment in Azure and devops tools such as Team city and Octopus.
- 12. Follow Coding standards as a part of CMMI level standards.
- 13. Strong in creating static and dynamic websites for clients as per requirements.

Experience

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

KPMG GLOBAL SERVICES

Senior QA Analyst and Application Developer

KPMG Global Services

Business Traveler

Title : Business Traveler

Description: Multi-national companies need to have visibility of their employees' travel and activities. They also need to understand the risk and compliance implications of travel, both for the company and the individual. KPMG Business Traveler (Business Traveler) helps companies and employees quantify the risk associated with entry requirements, income tax, social tax, and permanent establishment. Joined the Project on APR 2017. Currently handling the complete offshore BA and testing for Business Traveler.

Tools used for Developemt: TFS, MS SQL Server 2017, MVC and Dotnet Core

Tools used for Testing: TFS,Visual Studio 2022,Burp Suite,Postman,LoadRunner,Fortyfy Scan

Tools used for Deployment: Azure and Devops tools such as Teamcity and Octopus

FEBRUARY 2019 - MARCH 2020

UST GLOBAL

QA Analyst and Developer

UST Global

Business Traveler

Title : Business Traveler

Description: Multi-national companies need to have visibility of their employees' travel and activities. They also need to understand the risk and compliance implications of travel, both for the company and the individual. KPMG Business Traveler (Business Traveler) helps companies and employees quantify the risk associated with entry requirements, income tax, social tax, and permanent establishment. Joined the Project on APR 2017. Currently handling the complete offshore BA and testing for Business Traveler.

Tools used for Developemt: TFS, MS SQL Server, MVC Dotnet Core

Tools used for Testing: TFS, Visual Studio, Burp Suite, Postman, Load Runner, Fortyfy Scan

Tools used for Deployment: Azure and Devops tools such as Teamcity and Octopus

JUNE 2017 – JANUARY 2019

XEROX INTERNATIONAL

Senior Software Engineer

Xerox International

DCC Xtract

The customers of Xerox places a bulk order for printers with a customised configuration. A Xerox representative collects a zip file (containing the existing parameters) from the printer device at customer location using the XtractClient. Xerox creates a customised configuration using the XtractWeb and generates the guide using VIPP. Customer needs to configure their new printers following instructions as per the generated VIPP guide

Tools used for Developemt: C#, ASP.NET, MVC5,SQL Server

AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2017

ORION INDIA SYSTEMS

Senior Software Engineer

Orion India Systems

ALex (Accounting & Auditing Lexicon)

Alex external is web application developed in MVC. It is basically to manage users in Alex web. This system handles functionalities like registration of user, Subscription of content by license, mange account etc. Another module in this system in Admin Tool. Admin tool will handle the license / user / organization approval process..

SEPTEMBER 2012 - AUGUST 2015

ESTRRADO TECHNOLOGIES

Software Engineer

Estrrado Technologies

Elvis - Campus Management ERP

Elvis is an exhaustive solution for Educational Institutions to manage their complete operations including student registrations, admissions, fee managements, TC management, promotions, Exams and result management, time table, attendance, library, parent portals, transportation, hostel management etc. Elvis is an ERP product built to work efficiently from any computers. All information - student portfolio, course registration, and library management, learning tools, admission and finance information is captured and stored at once, eliminating data re-entry, reducing errors and resulting better productivity.

Tools used for Developemt: C#, ASP.NET, MVC,SQL Server, Crystal Reports

Educational Qualifications

2007 - 2011

Bachelor of Technology

Bachelor of Computer Science

UNIVERSITY OF KERALA - INDIA

LOURDES MATHA COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

2005 - 2007

High School

Science and Mathematics

KERALA STATE SECONDARY BOARD - INDIA

BETHANY ST JOHNS ENGLISH HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Certifications

- 1. Microsoft Azure Fundamentals AZ-900
- 2. ISTQB UK and Ireland testing Board
- 3. Power BI and Business Analyst

Contact Details

Mobile: +91 9947311713

Email: sarathprakashofficial@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sarath-prakash-751a27229

Website: http://sarathprakash.com

Skype:sarathnmzDUF Number:2022 053514 06Norway Visa Number:004168204

Personal Details

Father' Name:

Passport:
V4106904

Nationality:
Indian

Marital Status:
Married

Language:
English

DOB:
23/03/1989

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above given particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

(Sarath Prakash)